# Shawn Anderson

Recent graduate of computing science at University of Alberta with leadership experience. Excited to adopt new and emerging technologies quickly and integrate them into projects. Special interests include:

Machine Learning, Software Practice, and Pure Math

## Work Experience

## Contract Developer

August 2016 - Present

Four Winds and Associates

- Development and maintenence of various web applications built in python with django web-framework
- Working from home, coordinating with another contractor, attending meetings and phone calls to acquire task specification

**Junior Developer** May 2015 – August 2015 Government of the Northwest Territories Dpt. Justice

- Informatics
  - Assisted senior developer in building and maintaining web components for the Justice website https://www.justice.gov.nt.ca
  - Developed a RESTful API using Scala with Play Framework to serve as the backend for online fines payment
  - Developed Wordpress Plugins in HTML/PHP

Helpdesk Analyst September 2014
University of Alberta September 2013 – May 2014
Dpt. Computing Science January 2013 – May 2013

- Extensive experience with Linux systems and networks
- Interpersonal experience in working directly and indirectly with users

Business Support Analyst May 2014 – August 2014 Government of the Northwest Territories Dpt. Health and Social Services Information Services

- Assisted senior analysts in maintaining and developing systems relating to a healthcare management database
- Developed a front-end system to display medical travel data using PHP, HTML, JavaScript and SQL

#### EDUCATION

2011 – 2016 Bachelor of Science Specialization Comp

Specialization Computing Science University of Alberta

2015 – 2016 Continuing Education

Machine Learning Stanford University (via Coursera.com)

Probabilistic Graphical Models Stanford University (via Coursera.com)

DEEP LEARNING USING TENSORFLOW Google (via udacity.com)



11007 -  $83^{\rm rd}$  ave Suite 903 Edmonton AB

587-501-3566

http://www.shawnwanderson.com

shawnwanderson

## Computing Skills

## **Datascience Toolbox**

Python Numpy Pandas Matplotlib SKLearn Keras Tensorflow Ipython

#### **Programming**

Python Linux Object Oriented SQL/DBMS Scala Git RESTful HTML/CSS C++ Vim Functional Tmux/Slimux

## Algorithmic Skills

Machine Learning
Reinforcement Learning
Graph Theory
Combinatorics
Convex Geometry

Neural Networks
Bayesian Modeling
Topology
Complex Analysis
Group Theory

#### Research

Instrument Recognition in African Music Field Recordings September 2015 – December 2015 University of Alberta

- Decomposed African songs into feature vectors via the open source signal processing tool Marsyas
- Experimented with various Maching Learning techniques including SVM, KNN, and Logistic Regression to classify which instruments are present in a song

## Movement Prediction Based on EEG Signals Using Hidden Markov Models

University of Alberta January 2016 - April 2016

• Given EEG data recorded on subjects in both rest and movement, my team generated a model to predict movement intention

## VOLUNTEER WORK

- Vice President Social Executive member of the Undergraduate Association of Computing Science
- Leader and Organiser of The Yellowknife Super Smash Bros. club
- 6 years coaching Basketball
- Math Tutoring